J.D AVILES

PROFILE

Senior Help Desk & Customer Service Advisor with 11 Years of Experience Resolving Complex Software or Hardware Issues. Over the years I've held Technician roles, Two Engineering Project Roles as well as Retail and leadership responsibilities. As Technology ever evolves, My curiosity drives me to learn new things and implement my expertise to help others. Currently focused on expanding my knowledge of Front End Web Development to apply in future opportunities.

EXPERIENCE

APPLE INC. CUPERTINO, CA

2015 - CURRENT

WIFI CI Infrastructure & Automation Technician Remote | Jan 2021 - June 2021

- Remotely Managed Test Lab with hundreds of test devices
- Optimized scripts to automate management of Infrastructure
- Experience submitting code changes via GitHub
- Tracking regressions and Following up with Engineers and Developers
- Signed off on Weekly Software Stability from Engineering code changes

WIFI CI Infrastructure & Automation Technician Cupertino, CA | June 2019 - Nov 2019

- Collaborated with developers and engineers on Software Impact to Customers
- Built and Maintained test lab with over 30 test machines & 300 test devices
- Submitted and Followed up with Tickets on unexpected software behaviors .

Apple Retail Technical Specialist Modesto, CA | March 2018 - July 2018

- Technical Appointments & iPhone Repairs
- Managed Backend Pickups & Stocking

Senior Technical Support Advisor Remote | March 2015 - Current

- Excellence Award for Top Customer Satisfaction & Efficiency
- Supporting all Apple Hardware and Advanced Software Troubleshooting
- Managing Tickets with Site Engineering
- Addressing Complaints, Feedback

BEST BUY / GEEK SQUAD MODESTO, CA

2009 - 2015

Credit Card and Operations Specialist, Managed Customer Service Returns. Advance Repair Tech for GeekSquad, Maintained in Store repairs and Managed Front end Agents

EDUCATION

CORNELL, WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE | COMPLETED 2022

SKILLS

- 10 Months of experience Software Engineering and Continuous Integration fundamentals
- Experience with Python, Command Line and Linux
- Deep Understanding of Networking Fundamentals
- Organized, Resourceful and Goal Oriented
- 10 Years of Technical Experience with iOS, MacOS, Windows OS and Ticketing Systems

- References Available Upon Request -